<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogger | Real Ultimate Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.realultimateprogramming.com//blog/categories/blogger/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.realultimateprogramming.com//"/>
  <updated>2014-07-15T22:20:37-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.realultimateprogramming.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hank]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Syntax Highlighting on Blogger]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.realultimateprogramming.com//blog/2008/08/23/syntax-highlighting-on-blogger/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.realultimateprogramming.com//blog/2008/08/23/syntax-highlighting-on-blogger</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may have noticed that my code blocks are suddenly
syntax-highlighted. You might think a tech-oriented company like Google
would have included something like this by default, but you’d be wrong.</p>

<p>My new syntax highlighting comes courtesy of
<a href="http://softwaremaniacs.org/soft/highlight/en/">highlight.js</a>,
which is great, although it does have some holes in the English
documentation. Unfortunately, I couldn’t find any place it was being
hosted for free, so I needed to set up a place of my own from which to
serve it. Enter <a href="http://code.google.com/appengine/">Google App Engine</a>.</p>

<p>App Engine is Google’s entry into the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing">cloud computing</a>
space; if you write your application according to their guidelines,
Google will run it on their infrastructure. As such, it is
massive overkill for serving up static files, but it’s free and
it has good reporting tools. So I followed the
<a href="http://code.google.com/appengine/docs/gettingstarted/helloworld.html">“Hello, World!” documentation</a>,
added the files for <em>highlight.js</em>, then modified my <code>pp.yaml</code> to add
handler for serving static files.</p>

<pre><code>- url: /
 static_dir: highlight
</code></pre>

<p>Note that this conflicts with the handler from “Hello, World!”; since I
didn’t want to serve up “Hello, World!” anyway, I just deleted the other
handler.</p>

<p>According to the documentation for <em>highlight.js</em>, all you should have
to do now is add one simple block of Javascript:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;script src="$PATH_TO_HOSTED_JS" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
 hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad();
&lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>This is technically accurate: this will cause the markup to be modified
to support syntax highlighting. That’s not enough for the highlighting
to take place, however; you still need to bring in the CSS for the
highlighting style you want to use (my two favorites are Sunburst and
IDEA).</p>

<pre><code>&lt;link href="$PATH_TO_HOSTED_CSS" rel="stylesheet"/&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>On Blogger, the best place to put this code is in the raw HTML for
your template; that way you don’t have to remember to include it in
individual posts that will have code blocks. One final note: your code
blocks have to be marked up by nesting a <code>code</code> tag inside a <code>pre</code>
tag—if you’ve done something silly like nesting a <code>pre</code> tag inside a
<code>code</code> tag, it won’t work. Here’s an example of the proper style:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
#!/usr/bin/env python
# -*- coding: iso-8859-1 -*-
print "Hello, World!"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>Back to flipping out…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
